Daniel Kneipp

Artificial Intelligence Developer

Contact

♥ 119 Gloriosa st., Belo Horizonte, MG 305190-490, Brazil



+55 (31) 9-9605 3234 daniel.kneipp@ outlook.com



in://daniel-kneipp github://DanielKneipp gitlab://DanielKneipp

Languages

Brazilian Portuguese
[Mother tongue]
English
[Professional working
proficiency]

Programming

C++, Python, R, JavaScript, Matlab, Java, Bash

Skills

Machine Learning:



Computer Vision:

Text Mining:

About me

I am objective and focused on results. With entrepreneurship in my veins, I spent many years studying and learning, from Convolutional Neural Networks to SWOT Analysis and Nash Equilibrium, trying to make a difference. I know that it looks like a Miss Universe candidate speech asking for world peace (joke), but I really work hard to do something that can change the game. Please, checkout my code repository (https://github.com/DanielKneipp) to see some cool stuff.

Education

2016-2018 Master of Science

Federal University of Minas Gerais (UFMG)

My research area is DNA Computing. The objective is to propose functional chemical circuits for classification tasks using Chemical Reaction Networks theory as a programming language and DNA strands as the hardware. I'm a NanoComp lab. Member (http://www.nanocomp.dcc.ufmg.br/).

2012–2015 **Bachelor** of Science

Federal University of Viçosa (UFV)

I received Presidente Bernardes Medal for my academic excellence (85.4/100). Final Paper: A Genetic Algorithm for Multi-Component Optimization Problems: The Case of the Travelling Thief Problem.

2010–2011 **Technician's** Degree

SENAI School

I Studied the basics of Computer Architecture, Software Development and Network Infrastructure.

Independent Courses

- Deep Learning Google | Udacity
- Machine Learning Stanford University | Coursera

experience

Full Time

2012-Now **LEHMAN BROTHERS**

Los Angeles, California

1st Year Analyst

Developed spreadsheets for risk analysis on exotic derivatives on a wide array of commodities (ags, oils, precious and base metals), managed blotter and secondary trades on structured notes, liaised with Middle Office, Sales and Structuring for bookkeeping.

Detailed achievements:

- · Learned how to make amazing coffee
- Finally determined the reason for PC LOAD LETTER:
 - Paper jam
 - Software issues:
 - * Word not sending the correct data to printer
 - * Windows trying to print in letter format
 - Coffee spilled inside printer
- Broke the office record for number of kitten pictures in cubicle
- · Learned how to make more amazing coffee on a new machine

Part Time

2010-2011 **LEHMAN BROTHERS**

London, United Kingdom

Summer Intern

Received pre-placed offer from the Exotics Trading Desk as a result of very positive reviews. Rated "truly distinctive" for Analytical Skills and Team-

work.

2008-2009 **Buy More**

Burbank, California

Computer Repair Specialist

Worked in the Nerd Herd and helped to solve computer problems by asking customers to turn their computers off and on again.

awards

2011 **Postgraduate Scholarship** School of Business, The University of California Awarded to the top student in their final year of a Bachelors degree. Mastered the art of filing accurate TPS reports.

communication skills

2011 **Oral Presentation** California Business Conference

Presented the research I conducted for my Masters of Commerce degree.

2010 **Poster** Annual Business Conference, Oregon

As part of the course work for BUS320, I created a poster analyzing several local businesses and presented this at a conference.

interests

professional: data analysis, company profiling, risk analysis, economics, web design, web app creation, software design, marketing **personal:** piano, chess, cooking, dancing, running

publications

article in peer-reviewed journal

Electronic Sensors for Assessing Interactions between Healthcare Workers and Patients under Airborne Precautions

Jean-Christophe Lucet, Cédric Laouenan, Guillaume Chelius, Nicolas Veziris, Didier Lepelletier, Adrien Friggeri, Dominique Abiteboul, Elisabeth Bouvet, France Mentré, Eric Fleury *PLoS ONE 7.5 (May 2012)* e37893. 2012

Reconstructing Social Interactions Using an unreliable Wireless Sensor Network

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury, Antoine Fraboulet, France Mentré, Jean-Christophe Lucet

Computer Communications 34.5 (Apr. 2011) pp. 609-618. Elsevier, 2011

A Real-World Spreading Experiment in the Blogosphere

Adrien Friggeri, Jean-Philippe Cointet, Matthieu Latapy Complex Systems 19.3 (2011). Complex Systems Publications, Inc., 2011

books

Microformats: Empowering Your Markup for Web 2.0

John Allsop Publisher, 2007, London

international peer-reviewed conferences/proceedings

Egomunities, Exploring Socially Cohesive Person-based Communities

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

NetSci 2011 The International School and Conference on Network Science, 2011, Budapest, Hongrie

Fellows: Crowd-sourcing the evaluation of an overlapping community model based on the cohesion measure

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

Interdisciplinary Workshop on Information and Decision in Social Networks, 2011, Cambridge, États-Unis

Fellows: Crowd-sourcing the evaluation of an overlapping community model based on the cohesion measure

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

Complex Dynamics of Human Interactions, 2011, Vienna, Autriche

Triangles to Capture Social Cohesion

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

Third IEEE International Conference on Social Computing, 2011, Cambridge, États-Unis

Electronic Sensors for Measuring Interactions between Healthcare Workers (HCWs) and Patients (Pts): the Case of Tuberculosis (TB)

Jean-Christophe Lucet, Guillaume Chelius, Cédric Laouenan, Adrien Friggeri, N. Veziris, D. Lepelletier, D. Abiteboul, Elisabeth Bouvet, Eric Fleury, France Mentré

2010 Interscience Conference on Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, 2010, Boston, États-Unis

local peer-reviewed conferences/proceedings

Communautés : Arrêtons de ne compter que les arêtes

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

13es Rencontres Francophones sur les Aspects Algorithmiques de Télécommunications (AlgoTel), 2011, Cap Estérel. France

Trouver des communautés socialement cohésives est NP-dur

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

13emes journées Graphes et Algorithmes, 2011, Lyon, France

Biais dans les mesures obtenues par un réseau de capteurs sans fil

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius

12èmes Rencontres Francophones sur les Aspects Algorithmiques de Télécommunications (AlgoTel), 2010, Belle Dune, France

other publications

Des triangles pour mesurer la cohésion sociale : Fellows, une expérimentation sur Facebook

Adrien Friggeri, Eric Fleury Séminaire w2s @ La Cantine, 2011

research reports

Finding cohesive communities with C3

Adrien Friggeri, Eric Fleury

Rapport de recherche RR-7947, 2012

Egomunities, Exploring Socially Cohesive Person-based Communities

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

Rapport de recherche RR-7535, 2011

Triangles to Capture Social Cohesion

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

Rapport de recherche RR-7686, 2011

Maximizing the Cohesion is NP-hard

Adrien Friggeri, Eric Fleury

Rapport de recherche RR-7734, 2011